A Finding Aid to the Jacques Lipchitz papers and Bruce Bassett papers concerning Jacques Lipchitz, 1910-2001, bulk 1941-2001, in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Jacques Lipchitz papers, circa 1910-1999; bulk 1941-1999; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; Lipchitz, Jacques, 1891-1973; Bassett, Bruce W.; 9.5 Linear feet Boxes 1-10, OV 11-12
  - Printed Material, 1929-1973; 1.9; Archival Resource Key; 1 Linear foot Boxes 7-8, 10, OV 12
    - About/Mentioning Lipchitz, 1929-1973; 1.9.1; Archival Resource Key
      - Books, Archival Resource Key
        - Les Sculpteurs Français Nouveaux No. 7, Jacques Lipchitz, Paris: ??ditions de la Nouvelle Revue Française, 1929; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 28)
      - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Archival Resource Key
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1930-1949; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 29)
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1950-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 30)
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 31)
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1964-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 32)
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 33)
        - Lipchitz Solo and Group Exhibitions, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 34)
        - The Lipchitz Collection, 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 35)
      - Lecture Announcements, 1954-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 36)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 37)
      - Museum Publications, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 38)
      - Newsletters, 1966-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 39)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1931-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 40)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1957-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 41)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 42)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 43)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 44)
      - Newspaper Clippings, 1965-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 45)
      - Newspaper Clippings, circa 1931-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 46)
      - Poem (photocopy) by Carol L. Kort, "In Memory of Jacques Lipchitz (1891-1973),", circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 47)
      - Press Releases, 1952-1972; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 48)
      - Programs, 1959-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 7, Folder 49)
      - Reproductions, Archival Resource Key
        - Twelve Bronzes by Jacques Lipchitz; 16 Collotype Plates with Introductory Note (portfolio), 1943; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 1)
        - Postcards, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 2)
        - Unidentified Publication (fragment), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 3)
      - Exhibition Catalog, 1970; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Oversized material scanned with Box 7, F34
      - Architectural Prints, 1958-1964; Archival Resource Key (Oversize 12)
        Oversized material scanned with Box 7, F24
    - Art-related, 1944-1969; 1.9.2; Archival Resource Key
      This subseries consists of a variety of printed items on general art topics, none referencing Lipchitz or his art collection.
      This subseries has been not been scanned.
      - Articles about Primitive and Ancient Art, circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 4)
      - Books on Miscellaneous Art Topics, 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 5)
      - Exhibition Catalogs and Announcements, Archival Resource Key
        - Other Artists, 1945-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 6-7)
        - Primitive and Ancient Art, 1953-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous Items, 1949-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 9)
      - Museum Publication, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 10)
        Oversized material housed in Box 10, F1
      - Newsletters, 1955-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 11)
      - Newspaper Clippings, Archival Resource Key
        - Other Artists, 1959-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 12)
        - Primitive and Ancient Art, 1962-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 13)
        - Miscellaneous Art Topics, 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 14)
      - Reproductions of Sculpture and Primitive Art, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 15)
      - Museum Publication, 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 1)
        Oversized material from Box 8, F10
  - Photographs, circa 1910s-1967; 1.10; Archival Resource Key; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 8-10
    Photographs document people, artwork, project sites and models, exhibition installations, events, and places. Photographs of people include Jacques Lipchitz, family members, and others. Photographs of artwork include pieces by both Jacques Lipchitz and other artists. Views of Lipchitz exhibition installations in the United States and Europe mainly document solo shows. Photographs of events record a variety of occasions, among them: the opening of Lipchitz's new studio at Hastings-on-Hudson, NY; the dedication ceremony for Philip Johnson's Roofless Church in New Harmony, IN, with ornamental gates and a sculpture by Lipchitz; and Lipchitz addressing an anatomy class at Albert Einstein Medical College. Among the photographs of places are Lipchitz's studios at Hastings-on-Hudson, NY, and Pietrasanta, Italy, and a view of Pablo Picasso's Paris studio.
    Additional photographs enclosed with letters are scattered among the correspondence (Subseries 1.2). Research materials amassed during the course of compiling both volumes of the The Sculpture of Jacques Lipchitz: A Catalogue Raisonné (Subseries 1.5) include photographs, negatives, and color transparencies of his sculpture.
    This series has been paritally scanned. Blank versos of photographs, photographs of artwork, negatives, slides and color transparencies have not been scanned.
    The series is arranged as 8 subseries:
    1.10.1: People, circa 1910s-1967
    1.10.2: Artwork, circa 1910s-1962
    1.10.3: Project Sites and Models, circa 1950s-1970s
    1.10.4: Exhibition Installations, 1950-1961
    1.10.5: Events, circa 1952-1966
    1.10.6: Places, 1956-1964
    1.10.7: Photograph Album, 1967
    1.10.8: Negatives, Slides, and Color Transparencies, circa 1950s-1965
    - People, circa 1910s-1967; 1.10.1; Archival Resource Key
      Photographs of Jacques Lipchitz include a small head shot taken during his early years in Paris, copies of two 1946 portraits by Arnold Newman, views of him in the Hastings-on-Hudson studio, at Modern Art Foundry, and with Yulla. Also found are views of the sculptor's hands.
      The Lipchitz family is represented by images of his parents Abraham and Rachel Krinsky Lipchitz, sister Diana, youngest brother Rubin, nephew Georgy Hay, a niece and her daughter. Most were tentatively identified in 2010 by Loyla Lipchitz.
      Among the other identified individuals are Josef Albers and Ken Tyler, Jane Blaffer Owen, and Fiore de Henriquez, a young sculptor who lived with the Lipchitz family in the mid 1960s. Photographs of Senator Robert A. Taft probably served as resource material for a bust commissioned circa 1958, and those of President Lyndon B. Johnson were likely used when Lipchitz designed the 1964 Presidential Scholar Medal.
      Additional photographs of Lipchitz and others are found among photographs of events (Subseries 1.10.5), and some may be enclosed with letters, scattered throughout the correspondence (Subseries 1.2).
      Items within folders are arranged chronologically; undated items follow in rough chronological order. This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
      - Jacques Lipchitz, Archival Resource Key
        - By Arnold Newman, George Moffett, E. H. Roth, and unidentified photographers, circa 1910s-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 16)
        - Hands of, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 17)
          Oversized material housed in Box 10, F2
      - Jacques Lipchitz in his Studio, Archival Resource Key
        - Paris, circa 1912; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 18)
        - Hastings-on-Hudson, NY (photographers: The New York Times and unidentified), 1962-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 19)
        - Hastings-on-Hudson, NY (photographers: Colton Photos, George Holton, George Moffett, Adolph Studley, William Vandivert, Whitestone Photos), circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 20)
        - Hastings-on-Hudson, NY (photographers: Roloff Beny, F. Roy Kemp, George Moffett, Bert Van Bork, and unidentified), circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 21)
      - Jacques Lipchitz at Foundry, Archival Resource Key
        - Unidentified Foundry (George Moffett, photographer), circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 22)
        - Modern Age Foundry (John C. Spring, photographer), circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 23)
      - Jacques Lipchitz at Emiliano Sorini's Lithography Workshop (Marvin Bolotsky, photographer), 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 24)
      - With Others, Archival Resource Key
        - With Yulla Lipchitz, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 25)
        - With Unidentified Exhibition Juries, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 26)
        - With Unidentified Individuals (Photographers: Bernard M. Cohn, Varian Fry, George Moffett, Carl E. Vermilya, and unidentified), 1950-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 27)
        - In Studio, Hastings-on-Hudson, NY, with Jane Blaffer Owen and Unidentified Individuals (Photographers: George Holton, Sacha Parma, Whitestone Photo, and unidentified), circa 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 28)
      - Lipchitz Family, Archival Resource Key
        - Parents, Abraham and Rachel Krinsky Lipchitz (copy prints), circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 29)
        - Other Relatives, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 30)
      - Others, Archival Resource Key
        - Josef Albers and Ken Tyler, circa 1964-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 31)
        - [Isidore Grossman], Studio Assistant at Work (Photographers: Sacha Parma, and unidentified), circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 32)
        - Fiore de Henriquez, 1960s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 33)
        - Lyndon Baines Johnson, circa 1963-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 34)
        - Robert A. Taft, 1950-1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 35)
          Oversized material housed in Box 10, F3
        - Unidentified Individuals, 1954-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 36)
        - Unidentified Groups (Photographers: Luis Guillermo Navarrete and unidentified), circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 37)
      - Oversized Photographs - Jacques Lipchitz, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 2)
        Oversized material scanned with Box 8, F17 and F21
        Jacques Lipchitz, Hands of
        Jacques Lipchitz in Studio, Hastings-on-Hudson, NY (photographers: Roloff Beny, F. Roy Kemp, George Moffett, Bert Van Bork and unidentified)
      - Oversized Photographs - Others, circa 1950s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 3)
        Oversized material scanned with Box 8, F35-F36
        Robert A. Taft
        Unidentified
    - Artwork, circa 1910s-1962; 1.10.2; Archival Resource Key
      The vast majority of this subseries documents Lipchitz's sculpture. Many are unidentified. Among the identified works are: The Joy of Living, Woman and Gazelles, Song of the Vowels (various locations), Prometheus (versions for the Philadelphia Museum of Art and the Ministry of Education, Brazil), Nôtre Dame de Liesse, Assy, France, and ornamental gates and a second cast of Nôtre Dame de Liesse for Philip Johnson's Roofless Church in New Harmony, Indiana. Photographs by Ladislas Segy include "Aspects of Lipchitz Bather III, 1917 bronze on the turntable," which consists of small photographs taken from 11 angles and glued inside a manila folder to document the rotating sculpture. Among the sculpture photographed by F. Wilbur Seiders is a detail of Lipchitz's signature.
      Other works of art by Lipchitz represented in this subseries include a substantial number of photographs of drawings, including pages from sketchbooks which are not among the Jacques Lipchitz papers. Also found is a photograph of a medal bearing a portrait of President Lyndon Baines Johnson commissioned for the Presidential Scholar Awards in 1964.
      Photographs of artwork by other artists include silver objects from the Jewish Museum shown in the Metropolitan Museum of Art's 1955 exhibition "Art of the Hebrew Tradition." The Lipchitz Collection is also represented by 13 examples of African sculpture. "Primitive and Ancient Art" photographs include identified and unidentified items from museums and unspecified collection; it is not known if any are from Lipchitz's collection.
      A substantial number of photographs of sculpture are among the records documenting The Sculpture of Jacques Lipchitz: A Catalogue Raisonné (Subseries 1.5); these have not been scanned. Photographs of artwork by Lipchitz and others, enclosed with letters, are scattered throughout the correspondence (Subseries 1.2) and were scanned with their respective letters.
      Photographs of artwork by Lipchitz are arranged by medium, as are those by other artists. This subseries has not been scanned.
      - By Lipchitz, Archival Resource Key
        - Drawings, circa 1920s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 38-39)
        - Etching, circa 1920s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 40)
        - Medal, circa 1920s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 41)
        - Paintings, circa 1920s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 42)
        - Sculpture, Identified and Unidentified, Archival Resource Key
          - Colton Photos (28A-5558), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 43)
          - James Moore, photographer, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 44)
          - André Morain, photographer, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 45)
          - Ladislas Segy, photographer, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 46)
          - F. Wilbur Seiders, photographer, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 47)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer (AA61-F56), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 48)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer (JL13-JL291), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 49)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer (JL306-JL398), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 50)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer ([JL]400-[JL]494), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 51)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer (JL511-JL857), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 52)
          - Adolph Studley, photographer (K43--Z51, and unnumbered), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 53)
          - [Adolph Studley, photographer](N89-Q46 and unnumbered), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 54)
          - Marc Vaux, photographer (12-698, and unnumbered), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 8, Folder 55)
      - Sculpture, Identified (unidentified photographers), circa 1920s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 1)
      - Sculpture, Unidentified (unidentified photographers), Archival Resource Key
        - [early 20th century], circa 1920s-1930s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 2)
        - #1-34, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 3)
        - #1-104, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 4)
        - Unnumbered, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 5-6)
      - Sculpture in Interior Settings, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 7)
      - Sculpture in Outdoor Settings, 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 8)
      - Sculpture in Outdoor Settings, 1961-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 9)
      - Sculpture in Outdoor Settings, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 10)
        Oversized material housed in Box 10, F4
      - By Other Artists, Archival Resource Key
        - Drawings, Unidentified, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 11)
        - Mosaic by Hilda Carmel, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 12)
        - Paintings, Identified, circa 1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 13)
          Géricault
          Goya
          Manet
          Nicolas
          Van Gogh
        - Paintings, Unidentified, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 14-15)
        - Sculpture by Dorothea S. Greenbaum, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 16)
        - Sculpture, Unidentified, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 17)
        - Silver Objects, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 18)
        - Lipchitz Collection, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 19)
        - Primitive and Ancient Art, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 20-23)
      - Oversized Photographs - Sculpture in Outdoor Settings, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 10, Folder 4)
        Oversized material from Box 9, F10
    - Project Sites and Models, circa 1950s-1970s; 1.10.3; Archival Resource Key
      A few other photographs of project sites, enclosed with letters, can be found scattered throughout the correspondence (Subseries 1.1.2).
      Photographs are arranged alphabetically by name of the institution commissioning the piece, followed by unidentified locations. This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
      - Hebrew University of Jerusalem (David Harris, photographer), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 24)
      - New Harmony, Indiana (Louis Checkman, photographer), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 25)
      - University of Minnesota, Duluth (unidentified photographer), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 26)
      - Unidentified Location (Lipchitz and others at same site; Cortlandt V. D. Hubbard, photographer), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 27)
      - Unidentified Locations (George Cserna and unidentified photographers), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 28)
    - Exhibition Installations, 1950-1961; 1.10.4; Archival Resource Key
      Photographs of exhibition installations, enclosed with letters, are also found scattered among the correspondence (Subseries 1.2).
      Exhibition installation photographs are arranged alphabetically by name of the gallery, museum, or institution sponsoring the exhibition, followed by unidentified locations. This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
      - Battersea Park (London), "London County Council's Invitational Open Air Exhibition of Sculpture" (Mann Brothers, photographer), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 29)
      - Buchholz Gallery (New York), Unidentified Exhibition, circa 1942-1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 30)
      - The Cincinnati Art Museum, "Jacques Lipchitz, His Sculpture and Drawings, 1914-50" (Edward H. Dwight, photographer), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 31)
      - First Plymouth Church [Plymouth, KS], Exhibition in conjunction with Symposium on Arts and Religion, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 32)
      - Galerie Claude Bernard (Paris), Unidentified Exhibitions (Photograpers: Robert Davis, Yves Hervochon, Luc Joubert, and Jean Michalon), 1956-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 33)
      - Gemeentemusea van Amsterdam, Unidentified Exhibition, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 34)
      - Gemeentemuseum Arnhem (Holland), "Sculpture en plein air,", circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 35)
      - Har Zion Temple (Philadelphia), "First Annual Art Exhibition on Jewish and Biblical Themes" (Freedman Photos), 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 36)
      - Musée d'Art Moderne (Paris), "Jacques Lipchitz,", 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 37)
      - The Museum of Modern Art (New York), "The Sculpture of Jacques Lipchitz,", 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 38)
      - Portland Art Museum (OR), "Lipchitz: Works 1914-1950" (Edward R. Martin, photographer), Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 39)
      - Rijksmuseum Kröller-Müller (Otterlo, Holland), "Jacques Lipchitz,", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 40)
      - San Francisco Museum of Art, "Sculpture by Jacques Lipchitz,", 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 41)
      - Stedelijk Museum, Amsterdam, "Jacques Lipchitz", 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 42)
        photographs with 2 diagrams of galleries indicating sculpture placement
      - Unidentified Exhibitions (Photographers: Bulloz, Japp and Maarten, O. E. Nelson, W. Van Suchtelen, and unidentified), circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 43)
    - Events, circa 1952-1966; 1.10.5; Archival Resource Key
      Photographs of The American Jewish Tercentenary Dinner feature President Dwight D. Eisenhower, the main speaker of the evening; Lipchitz does not appear in any views. At the award ceremony sponsored by the Philadelphia Museum School of Art, a citation was presented to Jacques Lipchitz "for the distinction brought upon his profession."
      Posed by Lipchitz's ornamental gates are the participants in the dedication ceremony for the Roofless Church in New Harmony, IN: Philip Johnson, architect; Jacques Lipchitz, sculptor; Jane Blaffer Owen whose Robert Lee Blaffer Trust initiated and funded the project; and chaplain to Queen Elizabeth, Right Rev. George F. Macleod of the Church of Scotland.
      The purpose of Lipchitz's talk to anatomy students at Albert Einstein Medical College was to share a new perspective on the subject of a practicing artist. From the early 1950s through the mid-1960s Lipchitz frequently appeared on "What in the World," a television show that featured experts who identified and discussed unusual items from the collection of the University Museum, University of Pennsylvania.
      Photographs are alphabetically arranged by name of event and chronologically within folders. This subseries has been scanned in its entirety.
      - American Jewish Tercentenary Dinner, New York City (Photographers: Alexander Archer, Wide World Photography, and unidentified), 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 44)
      - Award Ceremony, Philadelphia Museum School of Art, 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 45)
      - Dedication of Monumental Gates, New Harmony, IN (James K. Mellow, photographer), 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 46)
      - Installation of Sculpture Commissions, Unidentified Locations, circa 1950s-1970s; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 47)
      - Lipchitz Speaks to Medical Students, Yeshiva University, Albert Einstein College of Medicine (Guy Gillette, photographer), 1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 48)
      - Opening of Studio, Hastings-on-Hudson, NY (Varian Fry, photographer), 1953; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 49)
      - "What in the World,", 1953-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 9, Folder 50)
    - Places, 1956-1964; 1.10.6; Archival Resource Key